# **Yassine Haimouch** — Frontend Developer

github.com/yassinehaimouch yassinehaimouch@proton.me linkedin/in/yassinehaimouch +212-6412-06132

#### **PROFILE**

I'm a software engineer mainly focused on React ecosystem. I have multiple years of experience in both UI/UX and Frontend Development. Over the past 3 years, I've strengthened fundamentals in web engineering that I'm eager to deploy on challenging projects to expand my current skill set and tech stack.

### **SKILLS**

- HTML5 | CSS3 | JavaScript | TypeScript | Node JS | React JS | Next JS | C | C++
- Tailwind CSS | Bootstrap | Styled Components | SASS | Redux Toolkit | React Query | Storybook | Jest | Tesing Library
- Git | GitHub | Bitbucket | Npm | Yarn | Web Accessibility | Responsive Design | Testing/TDD | Vim | Linux | Vercel | Netlify
- Figma | Adobe Photoshop | Adobe Illustrator | Adobe XD

#### **EXPERIENCE**

Software Engineer & Content Creator, Gitcoder - instagram.com/gitcoder/

April 2022 - Present

Software Engineering, Tech Life, Coding, Resources, Blogging

### Frontend Engineer & Freelancer, Upwork | Instagram

May 2019 - Present

- Building responsive and user-friendly websites and web applications from scratch using a (Figma, React JS, Tailwind).
- Building familiarity with git workflow, Testing/TDD, Performance Optimization.
- Maintaining open communication with clients throughout the project to ensure their satisfaction and delivering highquality work within specified deadlines.
- Focusing on writing clean, maintainable and reusable code.

#### Software Engineer, 1337 School - 42 Network

June 2021 - July 2021

- Engaged in an intensive and immersive coding boot camp program, designed to assess and develop coding skills.
- · Completed a series of challenging coding projects and exercises within strict time limits, fostering problem-solving abilities and time management skills.
- Collaborated with a diverse group of peers to solve complex programming challenges, enhancing teamwork and communication skills.
- Demonstrated adaptability and resilience by thriving in a demanding and competitive environment.
- Developed a strong foundation in programming concepts and practices through hands-on learning and self-directed study.
- Evaluated suitability for the full-time program at the 1337 School, showcasing commitment to further education and growth in the field of coding.

### **EDUCATION**

Epic React Dev, Course by Kent C. Dodds

High School Diploma, Physics

2017 - 2018

Moroccan — Diploma

## **PROJECTS**

**Bookshelf:** Building a full React application from scratch using (React JS, React Query, Bootstrap).

Advanced React Patterns: Built simple and flexible React Components and Hooks using modern patterns.

Rick & Morty: Developed a project that consumes The Rick and Morty API to create a visually appealing interface showcasing all characters from the show.

Portfolio: Designed and developed my portfolio using Figma, React JS, Tailwind CSS, Framer Motion.

E-Commerce Card View: Implemented dynamic functionality to compute and display the cumulative pricing of selected items in real-time.